rentalsystems.com 2017-02-28

# Cookies and Privacy Policy | Rentalsystems

**Your personal data**

To be able to process bookings we need to collect certain personal details from you. These details will include, where applicable:

1\. In the case of a Renter:  the names of the Renter and members of the Renter’s Party, their ages, at least the Renter’s contact details (including email address), at least the Renter’s credit/debit card details, etc which we do not store; and

2\. In the case of an Owner: the Owner’s name, contact details (including email address), bank account details, details of the Property

If we need further personal data we will ask for them. 

We use the contact details to communicate with the Owner and Renter. 

If you make an order or purchase goods or services through our website, such as a purchase of our Non-Refundable Breakage Waiver, we may disclose to the supplier of the goods or service your personal information to our partners, suppliers and sub-contractors in order to process your order, fulfil deliveries, compete billing and invoicing transactions and to enable delivery and logistics to be planned and delivered efficiently.  

We may supply your personal data to trusted suppliers who undertake analysis for us. 

We may also pass your personal data to other third parties (including, without limitation, our Affiliates) if necessary in order to arrange for a booking to be provided or enquiry answered or to process a booking in a way contemplated by our website. 

In some cases we may pass information, including your personal data, to third parties outside the European Economic Area. These countries may not provide the same level of protection for your personal data as the UK. If we do transfer your data outside the European Economic Area we will put in place a contract to ensure, so far as reasonably possible, that your information is protected or, where applicable, covered by the US “Safe Harbour Program”.

**Consents**

By entering your personal data onto our website, you agree to your personal data being processed in these ways. If you are a Renter you agree that you are authorised to disclose to us personal data about your Renter’s Party and that we may use such personal data in the same way as if it were your personal data.

If you have subscribed to our e-mail service or have made a booking for, or an enquiry about, the services we offer, you agree we may send you targeted promotional e-mails about the services and special deals we offer unless you have opted out of receiving these. 

You agree that we may also disclose our customer database, including any personal data relating to you contained in it, to a third party who acquires or attempts to acquire all or substantially all of the assets or shares in Clickstay Ltd. or our website whether by merger, acquisition, reorganisation or otherwise.

**Updating your personal data**

Please ensure that you keep your personal data up to date.

We store details of your personal data and transactional information against your personal profile. We keep your personal data for such periods of time as we consider to be necessary for us to provide our services.

If you post a comment on our website, or send a comment to us by email, text message or phone, or by letter or other means, we may display this content indefinitely in any relevant context. This will be anonymised in the case of testimonials or customer services conversations.

When you give information about another person, you confirm that that person has appointed you to act in that way and to consent to the processing of that person’s personal data, in the ways described above as if it were your personal data including, without limitation, to the transfer of that data outside the European Economic Area.

**Disclosure**

We may disclose your personal data where we are obliged or permitted by law to do so. If you send offensive messages or objectionable content on or via our website or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on our website, we may use the information that we have about you to stop this behaviour. We may, without limitation, inform law enforcement agencies and (if appropriate) your employer about your behaviour.

**Information requests**

You are generally entitled to ask us (by letter or e-mail) what details of yours are being held or processed, for what purpose and to whom they may be or have been disclosed. We will charge a small processing fee to cover the cost of our responding to such a request. We promise to respond to your request within 40 days of receiving your written request and fee. In certain limited circumstances we are entitled to refuse your request. 

If you believe that any of your personal details which we are processing are inaccurate or incorrect please contact us immediately. 

This privacy statement covers websites owned and controlled by us only. Links to other websites and any information collected by these sites are not covered by this privacy statement. As our privacy statement may change due to developments in the law, we would encourage you to reread our privacy statement from time to time so that you are aware of any changes in how we gather and use personal information.

**Cookies**

We may send you a cookie when you visit [www.clickstay.com](http://www.clickstay.com/) or any of our other websites.  

A ‘cookie’ is a very small file that is placed on your computer, tablet or mobile device. There are two categories of cookie, called “first party” and “third party” cookies:

1\. First Party cookies are cookies that we set and we use them for a number of reasons, such as remembering who you are when you return to our Website; and  

2\. Third Party cookies are cookies set on our behalf by third parties such as Google. These cookies do not collect your personal data and you cannot be identified as an individual customer from them.

We use cookies for a number of different reasons, which are:

1\. Essential cookies:  These are cookies that are necessary for our websites to work and cannot be switched off. They are usually only set in response to actions that you make, such as when you log in to check your booking. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information.   
You can set your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but if you do, some parts of our Websites will not work properly. 

2\. Performance cookies: This type of cookie allows us to count the number of times you visit our website and how you came to our website. We use these cookies to identify which pages of our website are most and least popular and see how visitors move around it. We may also use this type of cookie to make payments to third parties with whom we have a contract when a visitor, who has visited a website operated by the third party, rents a property or buys a service using our website.   
We use Google Analytics to provide this service. The data they collect is not shared with anyone else. The information is anonymised and we do not attempt to use it to identify any individual visitor to our website, or influence your use of our website when you use it. 

**How to control the use of cookies**

You are not obliged to accept cookies and you may change the settings in your browser so that it will not accept cookies. You can control cookies by (i) allowing them, (ii) deleting them individually or (iii) deleting all of them. You can also set your browser not to accept them at all. If you choose not to accept them at all, our website may not function properly or at all.  It may also be possible for you to set your browser so that it notifies you before you accept a cookie. If you do this, it may mean that browsing our website is slower than if you choose a different option.

It may be possible for you to change the settings of your browser to prevent just third party cookies from being placed on your computer, tablet or device:  In some browsers, it may even be possible to block cookies from specific companies or organisations.

To control the use of cookies, please follow the instructions on the browser you use on your computer, tablet or device.

You may also be able to control the use of cookies by opting out of online behavioural advertising by visiting the “Your Online Choices” page of the website provided by the Internet Advertising Bureau.

If our website uses Macromedia Flash Player, a small flash cookie may be placed on your computer, tablet or device. Flash cookies are stored in a different location on your computer than other types of cookie and, as a result, it is not possible to manage or block this type of cookie by adjusting the settings on your browser.

**Web beacons and URL tracking**

We may track URLs to count the number of clicks on a webpage, so that we can assess the popularity of a webpage.

In addition, we may use web beacons. A web beacon is a file that tracks the number of users on a page and allows us to see if a cookie has been activated or if an email has been delivered successfully and read. 

It is not possible for you change the settings on your browser to decline web beacons. If you change the settings to disable cookies, you can prevent web beacons from monitoring your activity. If you set your browser to disable cookies, our website may not, however, work properly.

**Changes to this Policy**

We may, in our sole discretion, make changes to this policy from time to time. This may be because the law or best practice changes or because of changes in our service or treatment of your personal data. We will display clearly on our website when our Policy has changed.

**Definitions**

In this Policy:

Affiliate

| 

means a person who has a website that refers persons who are interested in becoming Renters to us.

---|---  
  
Owner

| 

means a person who owns a Property that is advertised on our Website for letting on a temporary basis.

Renter

| 

means a person who agrees to rent a Property on a temporary basis via our Website.

Renter’s Party

| 

means the individuals identified by the Renter as those who  will occupy the Property on a temporary basis (including any additional person(s) or substitute person(s) agreed with the Owner).

We/us/our

| 

means Clickstay Ltd., a private company, limited by shares and incorporated in England and Wales under number 8674663, whose registered office is at Astral House, Granville Way, Bicester, Oxfordshire, United Kingdom OX26 4JY. Reference to Clickstay shall be deemed to include a reference to its successors and assigns.

Website

| 

means clickstay.com, rentalsystems.com and any other website operated by us.

You, your

| 

refers to an Owner or a Renter, as the case may be.

_Last Changed:  1st December 2014_
